Guide to the Richard Aldington Collection
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Richard Aldington collection
1918-1962
GEN MSS 321
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
0.6
(2 boxes)
Correspondence and writings by Aldington. The correspondence consists of seven folders of letters written by Richard and Catherine Aldington to Eunice Black Gluckman dating from 1932 to 1962. There are also 28 letters by Richard Aldington to Crosby Gaige, and approximately fifteen letters to various other people, including five to Bernhard Knollenberg. The writings consist of drafts, layouts, and proofsheets of articles and poems by Aldington.
Aldington, Richard, 1892-1962
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Ongoing collection of documents acquired by gift and purchase from various sources. Source information is recorded on the folders. For further information, consult the appropriate curator.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Scope and Contents
This finding aid encompasses accessions of single manuscripts and small groups of manuscripts and other papers, by or pertaining to Richard Aldington, acquired by the library from a variety of sources. Materials incorporated into the collection prior to September 1997 have been organized into two series, Correspondence and Writings.
Imagist poetry; Poetry; Fifty Romance Lyric Poems; Voltaire; The Eaten Heart; The Love of Myrrhine and Konallis and other Prose Poems; Aldington, Catherine; Aldington, Richard, 1892-1962; Gaige, Crosby, 1882-1949; Gluckman, Eunice Black; Knollenberg, Bernhard, 1892-1973
- Correspondence, 1918-1962; Series I; 0.2' (1 box)
  - TLS to Mr. [Crosby] Gaige, Padworth, Nr. Reading, Berks, 1927 Jun 1 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Scope and Contents
    Includes: Photograph of Aldington. Enclosing an account with Pascal Covici, publisher, for the sale of his Love of Myrrhine and Konallis. Chicago, 1926
  - 26 TLS and ALS, and 1 autograph postcard to Crosby Gaige, concerning publishing and literary matters, England and France, 1926-33 (Box 1, Folder 2-3)
    Enclosed are carbon copies of a brief correspondence between Richard Aldington and George H. Doran; copies of several of Mr. Aldington's original poems and translations; and the proof [?] of the title-page of his Fifty Romance Lyric Poems, New York: Crosby Gaige, London, William Heinemann, Ltd., 1927
  - TLS to Norman Keill, Montpellier, France, 1956 Feb 9 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - 1 ALS and 4 TLS to Bernhard Knollenberg, Dupont Circle, Washington, D.C., Old Lyme, CT, Jamay Beach, Nokomis, FL, 1940-42 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - ALS to Elkin Mathews, [London], [1919 Mar?] (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Removed from his Images of Desire, London, 1919
  - TLS to [H. M. Tomlinson], editor of The Nation, Newbury, Berks, 1920 Nov 19 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Acc #: 920701-m
  - TLS (photostat) to William Yale, Montpellier, France, 1955 Nov 7 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    Concerning Richard Aldington's Lawrence of Arabia
  - 3 ALS to "Dear May," [v.p.], 1919, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 9)
    About Amy Lowell
  - ALS to an unidentified recipient, [London], 1918 Nov 30 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    Removed from his The Poets' Translation Series. First Series
  - Letters to Eunice Black Gluckman, 1932-36 (Box 1, Folder 11-13)
    Acc #: 900529-b
  - Letters to Eunice Black Gluckman, 1955-62 (Box 1, Folder 14-16)
    Includes: Two photographs of RA
  - Letters from Catherine Aldington to Eunice Black Gluckman, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    Includes: Photograph of RA and CA
- Writings, 1930; Series II; 0.4'(1 box)
  - "Algeria," typescript of an article, with autograph manuscript corrections, [ca. 1930] (Box 2, Folder 18)
    With this are bound: layout of article, with autograph notes, and and photographs pasted on layout. Proofsheets, with autograph corrections. Bound in gray paper boards
  - The Eaten Heart and Other Poems, typed manuscript with author's corrections (Box 2, Folder 19)
    From the library of Crosby Gaige, with his book label
  - Fifty Romance Lyrics, typed manuscript with author's corrections, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 20-22)
  - "Hymn to Apollo," typescript, carbon, corrected and signed by the author (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - The Love of Myrrhine and Konallis, and Nineteen Prose Poems, typed manuscript with author's corrections (Box 2, Folder 24-25)
    Accompanied by a TLS to Pascal Covici, Malthouse Cottage, Padworth, Near Reading, Berks., Dec 19, 1924
  - "A Roman Letter," typed manuscript, with the author's corrections, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 26)
    Accompanied by 2 ANS to Mr. May, Authors' Club, 2 Whitehall Court, S.W.1 [London] Apr 29, 1919; May 23, 1919
  - "Voltaire," autograph manuscript, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 27-28)